Hi everyone, I'm Susie Woo
大家好 我是戴舒萱
I'm from the UK
我來自英國
Welcome back to my channel
歡迎回到我的頻道
It's another enrollment period for our
現在又到了全方位英語文化課程報名期間
Learn English Through UK Culture Course
So for you intermediate
所以如果你是中級到高級的英文學習者
to advanced English learners
who want to improve your English
而且你想提升你的英文
in the most effective
用最有效率
and the most interesting way possible,
也最有趣的方式
you can join now
你現在就可以加入
But there are limited places
但是名額有限
and there's only a limited period of time
而且可以報名的時間
that you can sign up
也只有短短一段期間
So if you enjoy today's video head to
所以如果你喜歡今天這支影片 就到
to check it out
看看吧
So boys and girls,
好啦 各位同學們
what are we learning about today?
我們今天要學什麼呢?
We're going to talk about
我們今天要來聊
We're going to talk about relationships and dating
我們今天要來聊關係和約會
This lesson has been taught
這堂課其實已經在Susiewoo語言學校教過了
at Susie Woo language school,
這堂課其實已經在Susie Woo語言學校教過了
but it is not in our full annual curriculum
但它沒有被放進我們完整的年度課程裡
into British life and culture,
也就是那套深入英國生活與文化的課程中
where we've condensed and optimised our best
在那套課裡 我們把最好的
learning materials into a year of learning for you
學習材料濃縮優化成一整年的學習內容
But I thought it would still give you a nice insight
但我想這堂課還是能讓你很好地了解
into the kinds of things that we do
我們平常都在做些什麼
So relationships and dating, part one
所以 關係與約會 第一部分
We have an alternating rota
我們的作業類型會輪流安排
of the types of homework
Sometimes it's speaking,
有時候是口說
so you need to do some research
所以你需要先做一些研究
and prepare something to say in class
然後準備一些東西在課堂上說
for just a few minutes
大概講幾分鐘就可以了
Sometimes it's reading comprehension,
有時則是閱讀理解
but what we will always have is
但每一堂課一定都會有的是
a video homework at the start of each class
課堂開始的一個影片作業
to get the discussion going
讓我們可以在課堂前討論
So in this case, we would
所以像這堂課 一開始我們會先讓你
start the lesson with you
either discussing a famous British building,
討論一個有名的英國建築
car or fashion brand,
汽車或服裝品牌
so that would relate to last week's topic
因為那會和上週的主題有關
Or you could focus on a particular design
或者你也可以改成介紹某個特定設計
or designer from your own country
或你自己國家的設計師
Or we're pretty flexible
或者其實我們也很彈性
You can talk about anything that you want
你想講什麼都可以
It's a chance for you to speak and get feedback
這是讓你開口說英文
from qualified teachers on your speaking
並獲得由合格的老師給你口說回饋的機會
So I'm gonna skip over the video homework
所以我今天會先跳過那個影片作業
because for copyright reasons
因為版權的關係
I can't show you the video in this video,
我沒辦法在這支影片裡播放那段影片
so let's just go through that
所以這部分我們就先略過
But what I do want to share with you
但我真的很想跟你分享的是
is the meaning of the ick
“the ick”這個詞的意思
To get the ick
This is a very specific phrase
這是一個非常特定的說法
that people are using at the moment for dating
現在很多人在約會時都會用
It's like they start to get to know someone
意思是你開始認識某個人
and they think
然後心裡覺得
oh, this person
喔 這個人
seems quite nice, quite interesting
好像蠻不錯的 也蠻有趣的
Maybe I like them
也許我喜歡他
And then for some reason, something changes,
但不知道為什麼 突然有什麼東西變了
something happens where you suddenly think,
發生了一件事讓你突然間覺得
oh no, I don't like this person
喔不 我不喜歡這個人了
And it can be the stupidest silliest thing
而且那個原因可能超蠢又超微不足道
like maybe they have a velcro wallet
比如說他用魔鬼氈皮夾
or they slurp when they drink through a straw
或者他用吸管喝東西時會發出吸溜聲
It can be honestly the most mundane of things
真的可能只是最平凡最無聊的小事
and that's kind of the joke with the ick
而這就是“the ick”這個詞好笑的地方
is that it doesn't have to be a real reason
就是你根本不需要有什麼真正的理由
not to like someone
去不喜歡一個人
You can just not like someone
你可以因為任何莫名其妙的理由就不喜歡對方
for whatever reason at all
It just describes that moment
它只是拿來描述那個瞬間
when you suddenly think, ew
就是你突然心裡想 噁
no, I don't like this person
不行 我不喜歡這個人
That is the ick
那就是the ick
Right, so lesson objectives for today are
好 所以今天這堂課的學習目標是
to learn about relationships
了解英國的感情和約會文化
and dating culture in the UK
Try your hand at being an agony aunt
試著扮演一個“agony aunt”
We'll find out what that means
我們等一下會解釋那是什麼意思
and as always learn more useful
還有一如往常地再學更多實用的
everyday phrases and vocabulary
日常片語和單字
Every week, there are 15 of these
每一週我們都會有15個這樣的單字
that we've specifically chosen
而且都是我們特別挑選過的
because they're so useful
因為它們真的非常實用
and so commonly used
也非常常用
especially in the UK
尤其是在英國
So you come away from each lesson
所以你每上完一堂課
with concrete words and phrases
都會帶走一些很具體的單字和片語
that you can start to use in your speaking
而且你可以立刻用在自己的口說裡
Now, this lesson starts with a bit of a discussion
好 這堂課一開始會先進行一些討論
How would you describe
你會怎麼形容你國家的約會文化?
the dating scene in your country?
So the dating scene is like how people date
“dating scene”指的就是人們是怎麼約會的
Is it relaxed?
是很輕鬆的嗎?
Is it quite strict?
還是很嚴格?
Maybe if you're from India, for example,
假如你來自印度
there might be specific arrangements
可能就會有一些特定安排
Maybe your family needs to attend the dates
也許你的家人需要一起參加約會
or maybe it's totally carefree
或者也可能是完全自由隨性的
and you can do whatever you want
你想怎麼做都可以
Do you think it's the same
你覺得和英國的約會文化
or different to dating culture in the UK?
是一樣還是不一樣的?
So we'll be talking about that in this lesson
所以這堂課裡我們就會談這個
and the last question for everyone to discuss
最後一個給大家3人一組
in their small groups of three with the teacher is
和老師一起在小組裡討論的問題是
do you watch any dating shows
你會看任何約會實境秀嗎
What's your favourite one?
你最喜歡哪一個?
And we will come to this shortly
我們等一下就會講到這個
Here, we have four words at the bottom
這裡底下有四個單字
and we need to fill the blanks
我們要把它們填進空格裡
We have
我們有
We have outright, spontaneously,
我們有 outright spontaneously
banter and cheesy
banter 和 cheesy
Now, you may not know what these words mean
你現在可能還不知道這些字是什麼意思
Let's talk about them
我們來講講它們
Neither men nor women
不管男生還是女生
stop each other on the street
都不會在街上攔住彼此
declare their love from across the road
隔著馬路就大聲告白
___ ask someone out
___ 約某個人出去
So ask someone out is highlighted
“ask someone out”這個片語被特別標示出來了
as one of the key phrases
因為它是我們這週要學的重要片語之一
for us to learn this week
To ask someone out
means to ask them on a date
意思就是約對方出去約會
For example,
比如說
hey, would you like to
嘿 你想不想
get coffee with me sometime
哪天跟我一起去喝杯咖啡?
meaning I want to date you
意思就是我想跟你約會
So because this starts with the verb ask,
因為這句話前面是動詞 ask
before that verb,
所以在那個動詞前面
we probably need something like an adverb
我們大概會需要一個像副詞一樣的東西
if you remember adverbs
如果你還記得副詞
end with y usually or ly
通常會以y或ly結尾
So it could be maybe cheesy or spontaneously
所以這裡可能是 cheesy 或 spontaneously
Now, spontaneously is like being proactive
那spontaneously就有點像主動
Like proactively going over
就是你主動走過去
and asking someone
然後去問一個人
You just have that feeling of
你就是有那種感覺
oh yeah, I'm gonna do this
喔對 我要去做這件事
I'm not thinking about it too much
我沒有想太多
I'm just gonna ask that girl out
我就是要去約那個女生
So this sentence is saying that in the UK,
所以這句話其實是在說 在英國
both men and women do not do this
不管男生還是女生都不會這樣做
We are not very spontaneous in our dating
我們在約會這件事上並不是那麼主動
So anyway, the missing word is spontaneously
所以這一題的答案是 spontaneously
In Paris, love is practiced as a sport
在巴黎 愛情像是一種運動一樣被實踐
at any given moment
在任何時刻都是如此
So it's a bit of a joke saying that in France,
所以這句有點像開玩笑地說 在法國
people are romantic all the time
人們隨時隨地都很浪漫
But over in Britain,
但在英國這邊
all that seems ___
這一切看起來就會顯得___
if not problematic
甚至是有問題的
Even eye contact is risky
甚至連眼神接觸都很危險
Here if not problematic means
這裡“if not problematic”的意思是
if it's not this first adjective,
如果它還不至於是前面那個形容詞
then it's definitely the second
那至少也絕對是後面這個
If not ___
如果不是___
If not problematic means
If not problematic的意思就是
that it could even seem problematic
它甚至可能已經看起來像個問題了
So the missing word is cheesy
所以這一題缺的字是 cheesy
Cheesy means like cringey
Cheesy的意思有點像尷尬
Like awkward or try-hard
像尷尬或做作
Like overly romantic,
就是過度浪漫
but with that cringey over the top feeling
但又帶著那種過頭又讓人尷尬的感覺
like wow that's too much
像是 哦 太過分了
So it's like too much, too romantic
就是太多了 太浪漫了
That's cheesy
那就叫cheesy
Nothing to do with actual cheese
跟真的起司一點關係都沒有
So in Britain, being very romantic,
所以在英國 如果你非常浪漫
can be seen as cheesy
就可能會被看成“cheesy”
and even more than that
而且還不只如此
it could be seen as problematic
甚至可能會被視為有問題
Like it is a problem
像是真的成了一個問題
and the last bit is an exaggeration
而後面那句其實是誇張說法
Even eye contact is risky
甚至連對視都很危險
It's saying we are so avoidant of romance
它是在說我們對浪漫這件事迴避到一種程度
that we don't even like
連互相看著對方眼睛都不太敢
to look each other in the eye
Obviously, that's not really true
當然 這不是真的字面意思
That's just an exaggeration
那只是誇張的講法
Like a little joke
就是個小玩笑
In the UK, I sometimes leave a date
在英國 我有時候約會結束後會覺得
thinking he doesn't like me,
他根本不喜歡我
but it turns out that he does
但結果事實上他其實喜歡我
British men won't tell you their feelings ___
英國男生不會___告訴你他們的感受
We have outright or banter
我們這裡有outright和banter
We could also use the word spontaneously here
其實這裡也可以用spontaneously
That would also be fine
那樣也說得通
Or we could also say
或者我們也可以說
British men won't tell you their feelings outright
英國男生不會這麼直接地告訴你他們的感受
Outright here means directly
這裡outright的意思就是直接地
Like a very direct confession
像很直接的告白
British people do not confess to you that easily
英國人不會這麼簡單地向你告白
Confessing your feelings
告白在英國不是這麼簡單的事情
is not that simple in the UK
Men usually will not say it so directly
男生通常不會這麼直接說
So what do they do?
那他們會怎麼做?
Instead sarcasm and banter
反而會用諷刺和“banter”
So what is banter?
那banter是什麼?
It's like playful teasing
它有點像帶著玩笑的逗弄
Like making fun of the other person
就是開對方玩笑
They might tease you
可能會取笑你
Like little jokes
像一些小玩笑
Like taking a dig or a poke at you
像是輕輕酸你一下 或戳你一下
Making fun of you in a light hearted, fun way
用很輕鬆好玩的方式鬧你
So it's supposed to be funny
所以它的本意是好笑的
And this type of humour is often seen as flirting
而這種幽默通常會被看成是在調情
And flirting is that behaviour that you do
而flirting就是那種
when you like someone
當你喜歡某個人你會做出的行為
Like hehehe
像是嘿嘿嘿
When there's that chemistry and vibe
當兩個人之間有那種化學反應或氛圍
between two people who maybe like each other
也就是彼此可能互相喜歡的感覺
and then there's flirting
那就會出現“flirting”
Next page here, we have three words
接下來這一頁我們有三個字
Chat, move and date
Chat move 和 date
After an online discussion
在一段線上聊過之後
that feels more like a ___ with a coworker
感覺比較像是跟同事的___
We could say like a chat with a coworker
這裡可以說比較像是跟同事聊天
You finally agree to meet for a drink
最後你們終於同意出去喝一杯
Never ever call it a ___
但千萬不要把它叫做___
date
約會
Again, this is a bit of a joke
這一樣有點是在開玩笑
It shows how avoidant British people are
它在表現英國人到底有多逃避
It might clearly be a sign of interest
明明聊天後和對方一起去喝一杯
in the other person
to go for a drink with them after chatting
很可能是對方對你感興趣的明顯訊號
But we would not say it's a date
但我們還是不會說那是約會
because we're afraid of that word
因為我們害怕那個字
It feels too serious
那個字聽起來太認真了
People want to pretend like,
大家會想假裝成
No no no, it's just casual
沒有沒有 這很隨意的
Almost like we're just friends,
就好像我們只是朋友而已
so then if it goes badly
這樣如果最後不順利
You can't say
你也不用說
oh, the date went badly
喔 這場約會很糟
It's more like oh, you know,
你就可以說 喔 你知道的
I just had a chat with someone
我只是跟某人聊了聊
and I'm not going to see them again,
然後我不會再見他了
but I didn't like them anyway
反正我本來也不喜歡他
So people are very shy and embarrassed
所以大家對表露感情這件事很害羞也很彆扭
to let others know our feelings,
不太想讓別人知道自己的感受
which is why you might not often
這也是為什麼你不太常會
hear people say that it's a date
聽到人們直接說那是約會
They don't want to reveal that
因為他們不想透露
they actually like the other person
自己其實真的喜歡對方
I know it's a bit stupid
我知道這有點蠢
and not everyone is like this
而且也不是每個人都這樣
Alcohol is ordered the very second you meet
你們一見面就會立刻點酒
That means like that exact moment
意思就是那個時刻
At that moment
就在那一刻
You meet and then bam, alcohol
一見面 然後砰 先來酒
In the largest volumes available
而且還要點能點到的最大份量
Again, exaggeration, kind of a joke
一樣是誇張說法 有點搞笑
and consumed as fast as possible
然後還要用最快速度喝掉
So you get the idea
所以你大概懂那個畫面了
Brits meet, they're like,
英國人一見面就會想
oh, awkward
喔 好尷尬
Need to drink a lot of alcohol immediately
得立刻喝很多酒才行
But nobody ever makes a ___
但沒有人真的會去___
Move
行動
So what is to make a move
那to make a move是什麼意思?
and why does nobody ever
還有為什麼在英國幾乎沒人make a move?
make a move in the UK
no matter how drunk you are
不管你喝得多醉都一樣
Making a move is like going to the next level
Making a move就是把事情往下一步推
So maybe like touching the other person
比如說去碰一下對方
or saying I like you
或者直接說我喜歡你
or maybe kissing them
或者乾脆親下去
or something that shows actual affection
總之就是做出某種真的表達好感的舉動
and like you actually like them
讓人知道你是真的喜歡對方
Again, this is just emphasising the fact
這一樣是在強調一件事
that British people can be quite shy and awkward
就是英國人真的可以很害羞 很尷尬
and avoidant of showing their feelings
而且很逃避表露自己的感受
So we're starting to get an idea of
所以我們現在開始有點理解了
what dating is really like in the UK
英國的約會文化到底實際是什麼樣子
And if we were in a real class I might ask you
如果這是在真的課堂上 我這時候就會問你
is being sarcastic or teasing someone
在你的國家 用諷刺或鬧對方
seen as flirting in your country?
會被看成是在調情嗎?
Are people awkward about the terms they use?
大家會對用詞感到尷尬嗎?
Like the word date
像是約會
And would someone ask
而且在街上會有人直接約別人出去嗎?
someone else out on the street?
Are people bold and brave
你們國家的人都很大膽很勇敢嗎?
like that in your country?
Obviously, we're mostly thinking of the US
當然 我們主要想到的是美國
On American TV anyway,
至少在美劇裡
they seem very confident
他們看起來都非常有自信
and okay with asking someone out
而且也很自在地直接約人出去
Like hey, want to go for a drink sometime?
像是 嘿 哪天要不要一起去喝一杯?
That would pretty much never happen in the UK
這種事在英國幾乎不會發生
It's all much more quiet, secretive,
英國這邊一切都更安靜 更隱晦
underhand and confusing
更偷偷摸摸 也更讓人困惑
Now, let's learn some
現在我們來學一些和約會有關的實用俚語
useful slang related to dating
Which of these phrases mean either
下面哪些片語表示的是
to end a relationship
結束一段關係
or to kiss someone passionately
或者熱情地親一個人?
So to end a relationship,
好 如果是結束一段關係
we have some words on the right here
右邊這裡有幾個詞
To break up with
To make out with
To get off with
To split up with
To neck on
To call it quits
To snog and to dump
To snog 和 to dump
or be dumped by someone
或者 be dumped by someone
As you can see most of them are phrasal verbs
你可以看到 大部分都是片語動詞
Phrasal verbs are incredibly common in English,
片語動詞在英文裡非常非常常見
but they can be difficult to use
但也真的很難用得自然
which is why we need lots of practice
所以我們才需要大量練習
So which ones mean to end a relationship?
所以哪幾個是表示分手呢?
We've got to break up with
首先是“to break up with”
That's breaking up
那就是分手
To break up with
分手
He broke up with me
他跟我分手了
and I don't know why
而我不知道為什麼
Now to make out with
接下來是“to make out with”
That one means to kiss someone passionately,
這個意思是很激烈地親一個人
but it's especially American slang, this one
但這個比較偏美式俚語
Oh my god, I saw you guys making out at school
天啊 我看到你們在學校親得超激烈
That was so gross
真的有夠噁
So what would we say in the UK instead?
那在英國我們會怎麼說?
We would say get off with
我們會說 get off with
This is very slangy
這個非常口語 很俚語
and something teenagers
而且通常比較像青少年會說的話
would be more likely to say
Like oh yeah, I got off with that girl last night
像是 喔對 我昨晚跟那個女生親到了
She is well fit, mate
她真的超正 兄弟
How about to split up with?
那“to split up with”呢?
Do you think that means kissing or breaking up?
你覺得這是親熱還是分手?
Well, split is like separating
split本來就有分開的意思
So that is breaking up
所以這個就是分手
You could say that the celebrity couple split up
你可以說 那對名人情侶分手了
That means they ended their relationship
意思就是他們結束關係了
Now, neck on is another way
再來“neck on”也是另一種說法
of saying kiss passionately
表示熱情接吻
Especially in the north,
尤其在英國北部
like they were necking on
像是they were necking on
means they were kissing a lot
意思就是他們一直在熱吻
Then we have to call it quits
接著是“to call it quits”
that means end a relationship
它的意思是結束一段關係
and it can also mean end other things
而且它也可以用在其他事情上表示結束
Like this game is not going very well
比如說 這場遊戲玩得不怎麼樣
Shall we just call it quits?
我們要不要乾脆就算了?
Like just finish
就是直接結束
Now, to snog
再來是to snog
Snog is a funny one
Snog這個詞很有意思
It also means kiss passionately
它也是熱情接吻的意思
It brings to mind that image of two people like
它會讓人聯想到兩個人那種
You know, just like
你知道 就是親得超級投入的畫面
really going for it with the kissing
Like too much and like a bit gross
有點太多了 而且甚至有點噁
and maybe saliva and stuff like that
還有口水之類的東西
So that's snogging
那就叫snogging
And then to dump or be dumped by
最後是to dump或be dumped by
So you might know that to dump
你可能知道dump這個字本來有
is like to get rid of something
把某樣東西丟掉的意思
In the US, they say the word dumpster
在美國還有dumpster這個字
which is like the rubbish bin
就是垃圾桶的意思
where you put your rubbish
你把垃圾丟進去的地方
or trash as they say in the US
或者美國人會說“trash”
So in this case, it is to break up
但在這裡它的意思就是分手
Like he dumped me
像是 他甩了我
or I was dumped by him
或者 我被他甩了
Again, it's quite casual slang,
這一樣是很口語的俚語
so you won't see this in formal newspapers
所以你不太會在正式報紙裡看到這樣寫
like the Guardian or the Times
像《衛報》或《泰晤士報》
You're more likely to see it
你比較可能會在八卦小報看到
in tabloid newspapers
like the Sun or the Mirror
像《太陽報》或《鏡報》
Ooh, okay
喔 OK
Now, we're talking about dating shows
接下來我們來聊約會節目
Have you seen these?
你有看過這些嗎?
Married at first sight and Naked attraction
《一見鍾情》和《裸體吸引》
Let me tell you what happens in these shows
我來跟你說這些節目裡會發生什麼
Single people take part in a social experiment,
單身人士會參加一個社會實驗
where they are matched with total strangers
在裡面他們會和完全陌生的人配對
by psychologists and dating experts
由心理學家和約會專家來配對
So they don't know the person in advance
也就是說他們事先根本不認識對方
and they're just matched together
只是直接被配成一對
They meet for the very first time
他們第一次見面就是在婚禮當天
on their wedding day
and then have six weeks to decide
然後有6週的時間決定
whether to make a go of
到底要不要試著把婚姻經營下去 還是分開
the marriage or separate
So make a go of here means to try it out
這裡“make a go of”的意思就是試著做做看
Try the marriage
試著經營這段婚姻
See how it goes
看看會發展成什麼樣
and you could also say
而且你也可以說
make a go of the marriage or dump each other
試著經營婚姻 或乾脆互甩
or call it quits or split up
或者到此為止或分開
All means the same thing
意思其實都差不多
So how would you feel
那你會有什麼感覺?
if you met someone for the first day
如果你第一次見到某個人
on your wedding day
就是在你婚禮當天
Like it's an arranged marriage
就像安排好的婚姻一樣
You meet them,
你見到對方
boom, you're married
砰 然後你就結婚了
Would that be uncomfortable?
那會不會很不舒服?
So in this show,
所以在這個節目裡
obviously, it is quite uncomfortable
很明顯地這真的會很尷尬
when they see each other
當他們第一次看到彼此時
and they might be like
他們可能會心裡想
oh, I am not attracted to this person at all
喔 我對這個人完全沒有吸引力
But now, we are married, yay
但現在我們已經結婚了 耶
Question, would you trust a psychologist
問題是 你會相信心理學家
or dating expert to match you with a partner?
或約會專家幫你配對伴侶嗎?
If you are dating, it could be quite helpful
如果你正在找對象 這也許其實還蠻有幫助的
to have someone say, hey, on paper,
因為有人會告訴你 欸 以條件來看
it seems like your personality and stuff
你的個性和各方面
is gonna match with this other person
看起來和這個人很配
Maybe it increases the odds
也許這樣會提高機率
that you will like that person
讓你更可能喜歡上對方
or maybe these things are very hard to predict
或者也可能這種事其實很難預測
Like on paper,
也許紙面上看起來你們應該會很合
it looks like you guys should get on,
but actually you meet each other and it's like
但實際見面之後卻會變成
no, there's not a vibe here
不行 感覺完全不對
Now, what is the show naked attraction?
那《裸體吸引》這個節目到底是什麼?
This is a very interesting one
這是一個非常有意思的節目
Worth a watch if you're curious
如果你好奇的話真的值得看一下
Basically, a clothed single person
基本上會有一個穿著衣服的單身者
So someone wearing clothes
也就是一個有穿衣服的人
is presented with a gallery of
站在一排
six naked potential partners
6個裸體的潛在對象面前
So literally someone looking for a partner
也就是一個在找伴侶的人
stands there in clothes
穿著衣服站在那裡
and looks around at naked bodies
看著一堆全裸的身體
Just the bodies
只有身體
and they can't see the face
還看不到臉
They are hidden behind booths,
因為這些人站在遮板後面
so they're sort of in a like box or something
有點像被藏在一個個小格子裡
Their bodies and faces are gradually revealed
他們的身體和臉會一輪一輪慢慢被揭露
in different rounds from the feet up
從腳開始一路往上揭露
So they start off by just seeing the naked feet
所以一開始只會看到赤裸的腳
and then they see the naked legs
接著看到腿
and then the bum and all of it
再來看到屁股 然後其他部位全部都會看到
Like all the genitals,
包括所有生殖器
so it is quite a shocking show
所以這其實是一個蠻震撼的節目
And then they go up and finally see the face last
最後才會一路揭到臉
At each round, the chooser eliminates
每一輪選擇的人都會淘汰掉
one naked person until only two are left
一位裸體參賽者 直到最後只剩兩個
So like incredibly rude and harsh, right?
所以這真的超級沒禮貌也超殘忍 對吧?
It's like oh, don't like your bum
就像是 喔 我不喜歡你的屁股
See ya
掰掰
What a weird idea for a show, right?
這節目的概念超怪 對吧?
The chooser then takes their clothes off
接著那個挑人的人自己也要把衣服脫掉
to make the final choice
然後做出最後選擇
So they also don't get away
所以他們也不能一路都穿著衣服
with being clothed the whole time
然後就這樣躲過去
They do have to take off their clothes eventually
他們最後還是得把衣服脫掉
So you end up with two naked people
所以最後你會看到兩個裸體的人
standing there together
一起站在那裡
And they are like
然後他們就像是
now boyfriend and girlfriend or something
好 現在我們算男女朋友了之類的
Very strange, very strange
非常奇怪 真的非常奇怪
So are you surprised that
所以你會驚訝嗎?
this is shown on British TV?
這種節目居然會在英國電視上播出?
You might think that should be X rated
你可能會覺得這應該是限制級吧
Like banned
甚至應該被禁播
Is it not like pornographic?
這難道不算色情嗎?
Well, it's obviously not porn
不過它當然不算色情片
It's just nudity,
它只是裸體而已
but it's still, I guess, quite inappropriate
但我想它看起來還是蠻不適合的
and shocking to see on TV
而且出現在電視上也蠻令人震驚
Here are some reviews about the show
這裡有一些關於這個節目的評論
This show is so body positive
這節目真的非常“body positive”
That means it really celebrates people's bodies
也就是說它真的很肯定各種人的身體
I love that they have regular people
我很喜歡他們找來的是一般人
instead of supermodel body builders
而不是超模或健美選手
The contestants are young and old
參賽者有年輕也有年長的
Fat and thin
有胖有瘦
Fit and flabby
有結實的也有鬆垮的
Flabby is like when you have fat
Flabby的意思是那種會晃動的鬆軟脂肪感
that kind of wiggles
It just goes to show that looks aren't everything
這剛好證明了外表不是一切
and everyone can be beautiful
而且每個人都可以很美
if they have a positive attitude and are confident
只要他們有正面的態度和自信
It's great to see people approach nudity
看到大家這麼自然地看待裸體
so casually and to discuss our bodies
而且這麼坦白地談論我們的身體
so frankly and honestly
我覺得真的很棒
So why does this guy like the show?
所以這個人為什麼喜歡這個節目?
Well he likes that it’s realistic
他喜歡的是它很真實
It's not just models and perfect people
不是只有模特兒或完美的人
It's like all sorts of
而是各種各樣真實不同的身體
different bodies that, you know
You've got big ones, small ones,
有大的 有小的
fat ones, thin ones
有胖的 有瘦的
Everyone is welcome
每一種都被接受
And they're not openly critical about bodies
而且他們不會公開批評身體
They just try and make it light hearted
他們只是想把它做得輕鬆一點
and fun and everyone is welcome basically
有趣一點 而且基本上誰都可以被接納
That's why he likes the show
這就是他喜歡這個節目的原因
Now how about this other person, Ross,
那另外這個叫Ross的人呢?
who gave it one star
他給了這節目一顆星
I'm no prude
我不是什麼保守到不行的人
A prude means someone who's very shy
Prude是指那種
about anything to do with like
對性或身體話題很害羞
sexual or bodily things
If they say I am no prude,
如果有人說“I am no prude”
it means I am not a prude
意思就是我不是老古板
But this program removes the mystery
但這個節目把原本的那種神祕感全拿掉了
and the old fashioned romance
還有那種老派浪漫
to meeting a person for the first time
初次見面本來會有的感覺也都沒了
It's almost like a cattle market
這幾乎就像牲畜市場一樣
So all the cows lined up in a row
就像一排牛站在那裡
and you need to choose
然後你得挑你想吃哪一隻
which one you want to eat
My 86 year old mother in law
我八十六歲的岳母
also watched it
也看了這個節目
Shocked and appalled
她感到又震驚又反感
That's a different way of saying
Appalled就是一種帶有負面感受的震驚
shocked in a bad way
That young people would be encouraged
居然會鼓勵年輕人
to go to such lengths on a TV show
在電視節目上做到這種程度
probably to get the ratings
大概只是為了收視率吧
So to go to lengths means to make the effort
to go to lengths的意思是花很多力氣去做某件事
and to do something
而且是做到超出平常的程度
more than you usually would
We both agree that
我們兩個都同意
this is one program to miss in the future
這是未來完全可以跳過不看的節目
So they really did not like it
所以他們是真的很不喜歡
They didn't like the fact that
他們不喜歡的是
people were like parading their bodies around
大家像是在展示自己的身體
to try and get approval from others
想藉此得到別人的認可
So who do you agree with more?
所以你比較同意哪一邊?
What do you think?
你怎麼想?
And this was a news headline, it says
而這是一則新聞標題 它寫著
a new low: explicit UK show Naked Attraction
英國露骨節目《裸體吸引》再創新低
causes a stir in the US
在美國引發騷動
So what does this mean?
所以這句話是什麼意思?
Well, a new low means
“new low”的意思是
the worst point or lowest level
情況跌到前所未有的低點
ever reached in a behaviour or situation
也就是某種行為或情況達到了最糟的程度
It's like there was bad
就像本來已經夠糟了
and then there's really bad
結果現在變得更糟
That's a new low
那就叫 a new low
And you can use this in speaking like
而且你在口說裡也可以這樣用
oh, I missed the train yesterday,
像是 我昨天錯過火車
but today, I missed a flight
但今天我居然錯過飛機
That's a new low
這真的是創新低了
and then the adjective explicit
接著explicit這個形容詞
means containing very clear
意思是包含非常直接
or detailed sexual content
或非常明確的性內容
It's like too much detail
就是細節多到太過頭
You can see everything kind of thing
像是什麼都看得到那種感覺
More detail than you want to see
比你想看到的細節還要更多
Especially, like nudity
尤其像裸體這種
Or you might have a song that says it's explicit
或者你也可能看到某首歌標註“explicit”
maybe they use a lot of swear words
可能是因為裡面用了很多髒話
and graphic language to do with sex usually
或很露骨的性相關語言
And what does to cause a stir mean?
那“to cause a stir”又是什麼意思?
That means to cause excitement, controversy
意思就是引起騷動 爭議
or widespread attention
或廣泛關注
So like people talking, people being shocked
也就是大家在討論 大家被嚇到
Like a big reaction
一種很大的反應
That's a stir
那就叫stir
So are you surprised that American audiences
所以你會驚訝嗎 美國觀眾
are seen as more prudish than British ones?
竟然被認為比英國人更保守?
So we've got that word prude again
所以我們又回到“prude”這個字
So it's like being shy or awkward
它就是指對某些事很害羞 很尷尬
or embarrassed about bodily or sexual things
或者對身體和性相關話題很不自在
Maybe if we think of stereotypes,
如果講到刻板印象
we think of Americans
我們可能會覺得美國人
as being more bold and outgoing
比較大膽跟外向
Maybe they would be more comfortable
也許他們應該更能接受
with a show like this
這種節目才對
But actually the headline is saying that
但其實這個標題在說的是
they did not appreciate this show in the US
美國人其實並不買單這個節目
And do you have any sort of show
那你的國家有這種節目嗎?
like this in your country?
I would be very surprised if you do to be honest
老實說 如果有我會很驚訝
So there's more to talk about here
所以其實這裡還有更多東西可以講
Agony aunt
知心阿姨
Agony aunt is when you
Agony aunt指的是你寫信到報社
write a letter into the newspaper
and someone usually
然後通常會有一位
an older lady who works at the newspaper
在報社工作的年長女士
She'll reply and give you
她會回信並給你感情上的建議
advice on your dating situation
So it's very interesting,
所以這個概念很有趣
but I'm running out of time today
但我今天時間不夠了
So I don't think I can finish this lesson now
所以我今天應該沒辦法把這堂課講完
As you can see,
你也看得出來
there's lots more interesting content
後面其實還有很多有趣內容
If you like this sort of thing
如果你喜歡這一類的內容
If you want to get stuck into British culture
如果你想更深入英國文化裡
and improve your English that way,
並且用這種方式提升你的英文
then I highly highly recommend joining our
那我真的非常非常推薦你加入我們的
Learn English Through UK Culture Course
全方位英語文化課程
It's all this sort of stuff
裡面全部都是這種內容
about different topics every week
每週都有不同主題
You can check out the curriculum online
你可以去看看網上的課程大綱
online at Susiewoo.com/culture
在 Susiewoo.com/culture 上
As I said, now is a time that you can enrol,
就像我剛剛說的 現在正是可以報名的時間
but it's a limited time
但時間有限
and there are limited spaces
名額也有限
That's because we have
因為我們只有非常精選的幾位老師
a very select few teachers,
who have been carefully chosen by me
而且都是我親自仔細挑選的
for their excellent chat
因為他們真的很會聊天
and teaching abilities and qualifications
而且教學能力和資歷也都很強
So it's great fun
所以整體真的很好玩
I hope you can join us
我希望你能加入我們
It's really practical
這堂課真的非常實用
It's going to get you
它會讓你的英文口說進步很多
speaking English much better
and also give you
而且也會讓你對語言背後的文化
a broad awareness of the culture
behind the language
有更全面的認識
Which for me is the most interesting part
而這對我來說就是最有趣的部分
So that's all for today
所以今天就先到這裡
Thanks for watching
謝謝收看
I'm Susie
我是戴舒萱
See you next time
我們下次見
Oh and by the way,
喔對了 順便一提
if there's a specific topic
如果你有特別想知道的主題
that you would love to know about
Maybe on this YouTube channel
不管是在這個YouTube頻道上
or maybe we can add it to our culture course
還是想加進我們的文化課裡
Do let us know
都歡迎告訴我們
You can drop us an email
你可以寄信給我們
or you can drop a comment below this video
或者直接在這支影片下面留言
We love to know what you guys find interesting
我們很想知道你們到底對什麼主題有興趣
Alright, see ya
好啦 掰掰